<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Christine Eunji Kim | Actress | NYC</title>
    <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Christine Eunji Kim | Actress | NYC</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:57:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://christineeunjikim.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding My Niche on Clubhouse</title>
      <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/210201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:57:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/210201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-a-confusing-first-week-i-think-ive-figured-it-out&#34;&gt;After a confusing first week, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve figured it out.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clubhouse is a new invite-only app that uses voice-chat rooms to connect people around the globe. It&amp;rsquo;s been picked up by people from all walks of life and is a source of infinite connections you&amp;rsquo;d never have made in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was invited to join by a friend who was moderating a room that would discuss AAPI Representation in Film. He thought I would add a valuable voice to the topic at hand. At the time, I only vaguely understood how the app worked. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even downloaded it yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fumbled my way through the app in the beginning, pressing all the buttons I could. Even though the community on Clubhouse was much smaller than the big social media names like Facebook or Twitter, it still felt unknowably large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, from the first discussion I participated in, I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./clubhouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart raced as I &amp;ldquo;raised my hand&amp;rdquo; in the room, and was invited as a &amp;ldquo;speaker&amp;rdquo; on the &amp;ldquo;stage&amp;rdquo;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite aware of the ettiquette yet, but the past year of Zoom meetings prepared me for muting my mic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation was more fascinating than I could have thought, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe that I was up there, engaging with all these wonderful speakers. The few times I unmuted to say my piece, my heart was in my throat. Thankfully, it being a voice-only chat, the rest of them couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the panic on my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was confused to see some of the other speakers&amp;rsquo; mute buttons blinking on and off while I spoke. I figured it was a way to indicate that they wanted to speak next. Turns out that&amp;rsquo;s how you indicate applause in Clubhouse! (Sidenote: Am I the only one who thinks of it as snapping?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go too much into the in-depth conversation Asian American industry professionals had about our represetation in media. It definitely went to some interesting, and possibly challenging places. Mad props to the Strong Asian Leads club, for always leading conversations such as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly joined so many (too many) other clubs. It&amp;rsquo;s exhilarating to speak to people around the world just about anything in just about any language. (Definitely giving my Spanish conversation skills a chance to shine!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming post-pandemic world, I imagine that social spaces may take a different shape. Everyone will be so much more open-minded to online interactions and I think that will bring new and exciting networking opportunities. Clubhouse may only be the beginning, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait for what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clubhouse is currently available for download only on iOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tired of virtual film shoots?</title>
      <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/201212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 11:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/201212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-little-creativity-can-make-a-remote-film-look-like-its-in-person&#34;&gt;A little creativity can make a remote film look like it&amp;rsquo;s in-person.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I talked about filmmaking during the pandemic. And it got me wondering: How can I create a short film with other actors remotely?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with remote filming by now. Even stories that are told completely inside a computer screen existed long before the pandemic. But this method of virtual storytelling has become a  crutch for writers during these times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to break that mold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I film a short, with other actors, without ever being in the same location as them? How can I use film magic to look as if we shared the same space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./poster.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All it took was a little bit of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote and directed &lt;em&gt;between|us&lt;/em&gt;, a short film about two sisters struggling to communicate. I worked with Nicole Jung as my co-lead, and had Kvlkar go above and beyond with the sountrack and sound design. All filmed virtually, no handshakes required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the final product looks as if we shared the same space. And that&amp;rsquo;s the beauty of filmmaking. I wrote a story that involved a common prop: a door. I planned out the shots and communicated with Nicole what I&amp;rsquo;d need from her. I edited the final footage together to combine our separate footage seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is how it turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BVrI1CqHWh0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For The Perfect Zoom Audition</title>
      <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200830/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 16:57:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-auditions-might-be-here-to-stay&#34;&gt;Virtual auditions might be here to stay.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportunity to be a reader in a callback session with an actor, a casting director, and the director of a feature film. And of course, it was via Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a reader is like being a fly on the wall &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;re not filled with audition anxiety, nor the pressure to cast the perfect actor. You can just sit back and observe. (And read your lines, obviously.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got me thinking about this new avenue of auditioning, and how you can use your existing skills as an actor to give the perfect Zoom audition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1-remember-your-self-tape-basics&#34;&gt;Tip #1: Remember your self tape basics!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a huge one. And one you already know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your self tape setup ready. You need your clean backdrop, you need your lights, you need your framing. If you can get your camera setup connected to your computer, that&amp;rsquo;s great! Otherwise, make sure that your laptop is at the right height and you have clear audio in and out. Ask your roommates to shush!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2-remember-your-eyeline-and-turn-off-self-view&#34;&gt;Tip #2: Remember your eyeline. (And turn off self view!)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be an extension of Tip #1, but it&amp;rsquo;s an important one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re auditioning via Zoom, you might get the Self-Conscious Eye Syndrome (there, I&amp;rsquo;m coining that term). You&amp;rsquo;ve seen it happen to others. Your eye wanders from one person to the other in Gallery View, and ultimately, to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid dissecting your audition before you even begin to act, turn off your self view. This is different from turning off your camera. The other participants will be able to see you fine, but you won&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you act, look at the eyeline you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared. (Oops, spoiler alert for Tip #3!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-3-prepare-prepare-prepare&#34;&gt;Tip #3: Prepare, prepare, prepare!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a professional actor, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you got the lines down. But are you prepared for everything that can go wrong on a Zoom call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you get on that Zoom call, do a picture check. Set everything up, and start a meeting with just yourself. Maybe even pull a friend into the call to make sure your internet doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut in and out. Nothing&amp;rsquo;s worse than spotty video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your laptop at the right height? Is your background clear? Where should you look while you act? (Try finding a point next to your webcam and put a small sticker to remind yourself later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-4-last-but-not-least-have-fun-and-be-professional&#34;&gt;Tip #4: Last but not least&amp;hellip; Have fun and be professional.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though you might be wearing pajama bottoms, this is a real audition. Treat it like one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also&amp;hellip; remember that we&amp;rsquo;re all new to this. If your background isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, or your neighbor won&amp;rsquo;t stop his tap dancing session, don&amp;rsquo;t panic. You&amp;rsquo;re here to give a performance, and that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you&amp;rsquo;re going to do great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filmmaking During A Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;filmmaking-is-more-accessible-than-ever&#34;&gt;Filmmaking is more accessible than ever.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should crave for perfection, but understand that we&amp;rsquo;ll never attain it. With that in mind, we should create. We all have cameras in our pockets. Filmmaking is within anyone&amp;rsquo;s reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest. When a short video hosting platform reached out to me to create a series of scripted videos for them, I almost declined. By this point, New York City was under deep quarantine and I was depressed that all my acting prospects went up in smoke. How would I create? I only had limited equipment, no crew, no actors. I felt like I had nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled with the decision for a while. But, as I do with most things in life, I grudgingly accepted the responsibility. And I’m so glad that I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity isn’t confined to the four walls of your apartment. It might even flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to tell a sweet, humorous story about an alien who came to Earth to learn more about the species. She came to find the definition of love. In vignettes, you can see how she sees the mundane world with fresh eyes of somebody who’s never experienced it before. The seemingly banal realities of life blossom into precious and memorable moments for her.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/1.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Episode 20, &amp;amp;ldquo;The Snack&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/1_hu2425cd34727aa6843c6c9299134fa55c_3404715_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Episode 7, &amp;amp;ldquo;The Delivery&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/2_hu2425cd34727aa6843c6c9299134fa55c_3812365_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/3.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Episode 8, &amp;amp;ldquo;The Storm&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200614/gallery/3_hu2425cd34727aa6843c6c9299134fa55c_3888556_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She doesn’t interact with anyone else on screen. She’s always alone, and she struggles with that too. But despite the physical distance, human connection is something that permeates the very air we breathe. We can’t survive without it. We couldn’t avoid it if we tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filmed this on my phone, with the help of a broken selfie-stick and my mom. Many kudos to her, she was able to get the shots we needed like a champ. There’s a strange buzzing sensation you get when you cross items off on your shot list. It felt great to have that excitement course through my veins again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My art will never be perfect in my eyes. But I’m proud of it regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://share.rizzle.tv/ty6b0l&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Definition Of” is currently available on Rizzle (iOS and android)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slate Your Name, Please</title>
      <link>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200319/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 19:00:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeunjikim.com/post/200319/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-those-unfamiliar&#34;&gt;For those unfamiliar,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;slate your name&amp;rdquo; is a sentence actors hear a whole lot in auditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can ask you for all kinds of information in a &amp;ldquo;slate&amp;rdquo;. Your height, location, availability&amp;hellip; And actors try as quickly as possible to display their unique personality. Then it&amp;rsquo;s over, and your character takes over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this website is a chance for me to do more than just slate my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want this to be a space where I can share my journey as an actor. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to be a highlights reel. I want to talk about my immigrant background and the hustle of surviving financially in NYC. I want to celebrate my wins and mourn my losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And maybe it will help others in my situation feel less alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the goal, anyway. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll speak more about my upbringing and my passion for acting in future posts. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you with this short first post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to the ones who dream.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
